[music]
Thank you. My name is uh Derek Ashmore.
I'm the Agentic AI enablement principal
um for Aspiritis Consulting, but I'm not
much for titles. You could call me
Possum King. I don't care [laughter]
about that. Um, basically I'm going to
start off with a story. Um, in and about
July,
I happened upon a blog post from Adrien
Cochraftoft. And I don't know if you
know him, but I've been following him
since the 90s. And yes, that makes me
old. Um, but uh, essentially he turned
me on to this Claude Flow thing. All
right. And he basically took Claude flow
which runs a team of Claude code agents
under the covers manages the team so
that you don't have to. All right. Um
and he basically described how he used
it to uh build a new application that he
was uh he was he was going to build. And
since I've been following Mr. Cochroft
for a couple of decades, I basically
followed suit. So I installed uh
Cloudflow and Claude code and I took a
uh complex uh Golang um project that I
wanted to make significant enhancements
to and I followed his lead. All right. I
basically
um in this world one of the things that
you do is you don't just say okay uh
Claude Flow go do this. You plan it
first. you piece apart the plan to make
sure that your instructions to claude
code and claude flow are um are coherent
and they do what you want and you don't
have any communication issues or whatnot
and ever since that experience
I was hooked all right and today this is
my preferred tech stack I work for a
variety of clients some of those clients
let me use this tech stack
some do not. Um, but if I have a choice,
this is the text stack that uh I will uh
go for. Um,
and of course
my screen decided to
time out on me. There we go.
And
it doesn't look like it's displaying.
Oh, there we go. [clears throat] All
right.
That QR code gets you to instructions
uh for the workshop.
Um, basically, we're going to start with
that repository. We are going to have
you fork that repository and establish
what's called a GitHub code space. using
that repository. Um I don't have any
religious affiliation for GitHub code
spaces but just as a practical matter um
leading a workshop I don't like uh local
environment issues right so it it it
makes it easy for us to have a common um
common way to uh to to run things.
And what we're going to do is actually
let me back up.
One of the things that uh Mr. Cochro
turned me on to was the concept of
planning implementations before you
actually do them. And I started doing
that with complex uh um code bases. And
the extent to which it investigated a
codebase and gave me a detailed plan was
just godlike and awesome. All right. And
so I started thinking, all right, if
this stack can do more than just code,
what else can I have it analyze? What
else can I have it plan? And today we
use it to do architecture work. We use
it to plan large projects. Uh we use it
to investigate code bases and let us
know what the uh nasties are in the code
base that we want to refactor, perhaps
fix, let us know what kind of test
coverage we have, that kind of thing.
Um, and so what we're going to do today
is a very similar kind of uh exercise.
Basically, what I did is I pulled a code
base um off of GitHub. It's an
open-source CRM type code base and we're
going to um analyze it and figure out
where the nasties are in it uh for um
modernizing it. Um basically
um
at modernization means different things
to different people. So let me park
there for a second. Um
by show of hands who has heard of the 12
factor principles.
Okay a good say 40%. Good. Um for the
rest of you um what those principles do
they were created circa 2012 by Heroku
which was balled out by Salesforce
and essentially what those principles do
is if an application codebase applies to
those principles or implements those
principles then it's very easy to uh
host that application uh wherever you
might want to. It doesn't have any um
ties to specific uh um operating systems
or runtime environments. But more often
than that, more over than that, it can
dynamically scale, right? So typically
when we get approached about uh app
modernization projects, what they really
mean is we want to move this thing to
the cloud. Uh what they really mean is
we want to dynamically scale so that we
don't have to um basically uh um buy
hardware for our peaks. We want to be
able to grow and shrink as as we want
to. And we want high availability
features, right? If this thing needs to
um fail over from US East one to US West
one, we want to be able to do that. Um,
in other words, what what really is
underlying the need there is usually
this app has gotten too hard to change
and it's gotten too expensive and we
need it to uh uh we need it to be
better. So, what we're going to do with
this open- source product is we're going
to do a 12-actor analysis on it. We're
going to see that it is a target-rich
environment.
All right. So there's there's lots of
things in it that don't fit well with
dynamic scaling. You'd be hard to um
basically keep it uh keep it highly
available whether you deployed it to any
of the clouds or to cube.
Um, and basically,
come on.
Um, so basically we're going to we're
we're going to get uh get the analysis
back and then we're going to go through
and we're going to say, okay, let's plan
an implementation. Let's say we wanted
to go through and we wanted to fix all
these things. All right, we're going to
have our Cloudflow team go through and
figure out um what it needs to do and
you're going to you're going to see that
what it comes up with is um fairly
robust. Um but we will get there
and there are a couple of things that
happen in that process. Often times when
we do a we plan a um remediation or
something along those lines, it does
something that we don't want and we go
through and we have it replan with
different specifics. Um no, I want I
really want you to uh put an automated
test harness in front of this that kind
of stuff so I can change it safely. And
then one of the things that comes up
with app modernization when they see
what uh kind of effort it's going to
take uh or when management sees that
usually uh what they uh somebody gets
the idea of um asking is can we move
these users to a uh a uh a different
product say a SAS product or something
along those lines. And it turns out that
my Cloudflow team can do product
analysis fairly well, too. All right.
It's a little bit handicapped in this
situation because in a real um product
analysis, you'll be able to tell
somebody uh or you will be able to tell
the team that okay, our users use these
features, but they don't really use
these features. um by not giving it that
kind of specifics um it my team has to
figure out has to assume that they're
using each and every feature which kind
of balloons the uh balloons the analysis
a little bit but we're going to see that
a little bit. All right. So hopefully
this has been up here enough. If you
surf to the QR code
um associated with that, what you will
get
is a uh repository.
Okay. And
while that's not glamorous in and of
itself, it contains a readme which
basically illustrates the steps that
we're going to do. But the first thing
we're going to do is we're going to fork
it because we're going to instantiate a
code space from it. Okay. So
I'm going to fork it.
I'm going to
basically call it.
All right. Um, one of the things that
you will figure out is that Derek
doesn't type and talk very well at the
same time. I've tried for years. I just
can't. So if there are a couple of
strategic silences while I'm typing that
is just inherent in the system.
Um and you only really need the main
branch. [snorts]
I believe that's all there is at the
moment. But uh at some point um very
quickly there it is.
Now after
after this happens the first thing you
want to do is up here in the lefth hand
column is you want to go to code spaces
and we are going to create a new code
space.
Select a repository
and I have access to
all sorts of stuff. So,
um I have to narrow down the list a
little bit. Now,
you can get away with um using the
default uh machine type of two cores.
What happens is the the code space will
scream at you when Cloudflow is working.
um it'll it'll tell you that it's maxed
and that uh basically it's uh it's it's
underpowered. So, it's not technically
required,
but I usually go with the four co four
core option. All right. And I will stop
slamming my uh um hand against my chest
because that's where the mic is.
All right. Um so basically
um this is this is going
um what
um I'm going to do
is get back to
our instructions to make sure that I
don't forget anything. All right.
Um, basically it takes it a couple
minutes to uh set up our code space. I
realize that this is one of the exciting
parts of the program, but it
it works.
Um, so basically after uh after this I'm
going to have you copy paste a couple of
commands from the readme in here that
will install um Claude flow that will
configure Claude our I'm sorry install
Claude code configure Claude Code
permissions
require that you log into Claude Code.
So, you need to have a um Claude code
account if you're going to going to
proceed with the uh the workshop. If you
don't happen to have that set up, then
you can look at the workshop as kind of
like a demo or something and you can go
through it just like the rest of us and
you can go through it at a later time
because I'm not taking that uh
repository away.
Um
and then basically after our a couple of
uh commands that we uh setup commands
that that we issue, then we're going to
start doing a 12 factor analysis over a
uh open- source product called IDM pair.
I'm probably butchering the uh um
pronunciation of that, but the code base
for that is actually in this repository
that you just forked.
Um what you can do is in real life, it's
not uncommon for me to have a uh a git
folder with three or four or five
different uh projects in it with a
single Cloudflow installation.
and depends on what kind of work I'm
doing. Um, but uh I wanted to make the
setup as simple and easy for everybody
as I could. Yes, sir.
>> Just to fill the time, you mentioned
some of your clients don't like this
text. Um, have they given any reasons
why they don't like this text and how do
you respond to those?
>> Um, [clears throat]
there is a complicated answer to that.
Most of our um clients are Fortune,000
companies
and large organizations have large legal
departments
and
saying that um Derek's going to come in
and uh expose your code base and have it
analyzed by Claude code which has an
anthropic LLM at the other end of it.
claudet typically or whatever the
version is now they're using. Um, that's
easier said than done.
>> Yep.
>> All right. Yes, sir.
>> Do you know flow works with AWS
profiles?
>> Um, it does. I've seen documentation
um to that effect. Um there are a couple
of specifics when you configure bedrock
that you need to um tell your bedrock uh
instance you need to point it to a
anthropic model one of the couple that
are sanctioned and there are a couple of
environment variables such you got to
set
>> yeah we've jumped through a bunch of
hoops to to get quad code working I'm
wondering if without jumping through any
more hoops I could just take
>> yes Yeah, I know. It's Yeah, it's same
as you have cloud code working in
bedrock. Cloud flow work. Cloud flow
works the same.
>> So,
>> yeah. And incidentally, as uh a couple
people have done, if you have questions
or concerns or comments, this is for
your benefit, right? Don't be shy,
right? It does it doesn't do you any
good to have Derek talk at you for an
hour. Um,
unless you want that. Um, but no, feel
free to pipe up and it is still going
>> operations down.
>> I'm sorry. What's down?
>> Git operations cloning
>> failures [clears throat]
like the server.
>> Jeez.
I couldn't clone the repo either.
>> Yeah, random errors as well.
>> Oh, what what error are you getting? I'm
sorry.
>> Uh the code space for Wanda basically is
running in recovery mode. Um the errors
like past this window, but it was
basically like it's running in recovery
mode. Like certain things are just not
installed. Uh and so I'm trying to clone
it and then manually to my machine. I'm
getting really bizarre errors I've never
seen. Uh basically.
>> Oh, so you're you're you're cloning it
locally and running it locally.
>> I'm doing both.
>> Okay.
>> So, is officially
>> GitHub is that?
>> Yeah. So, this morning was claw. No, it
was cloud. So,
>> okay.
You know
>> what if you zip your put it on?
>> You can fork it. I fork it.
>> For you would work.
>> Okay.
>> Just type it in.
>> When you work, you should be able to
download the repo as a zip.
>> Try that.
Yeah,
>> that works.
>> You can't clone the repo or you can't
fork the repo.
>> It's unhealthy upstream. Uh neither. You
can't clone it. Uh I don't know about
forking it. I think I was able to fork
it, but get the code space
>> working.
>> But yeah, I'm see.
>> It does look like the zip.
>> I mean, it's got it got a zip file with
code in it. any dangerous stuff in there
besides the
>> No, there's
>> there's no there's no dangerous stuff in
there.
>> ID.
>> No,
>> for those who can probably do have a dev
container in there. So if you want it
because it's running code spaces. So for
those probably be able to run it in a
container locally. But
>> yeah, that's that's that that's true
too. I haven't uh I haven't tried that.
and you don't really
care about
All right.
So, note to self, I have a backup for
all services next year.
because I just went through this a few
days ago.
>> Again, it's a global on.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. I am going to
even with the errors what I'm going to
do is install cloud code and see what
issues it gives me.
Okay, it did install it correctly. Let's
see what um after you install cloud
code, the next thing you need to do, and
one of the reasons why I elected for
code spaces is um because I'm telling
Claude to in this installation to
dangerously skip permissions
because that is a real pain.
When you do that,
um, it basically,
um, wants me to log in. So, I prefer
dark mode, but you don't feel, um,
constrained to do that. I log into
clawed account with my uh, subscription.
Um, it gives me something and it gives
me an option to open it. I have never
[snorts] um I've had better luck with
just copy pasting the um Earl.
And I'm going to authorize my code
space.
And I get this occasionally. Sometimes
Claude doesn't um
Claude doesn't um cooperate the first
time. Sometimes I need to go through
this two or three times,
which I shouldn't have to, but
is [snorts] this the definition of
insanity? doing something uh repeatedly
and expecting
>> doing a call back to local host, right?
Is that correct? That
>> that's that that's correct. But you
normally see that
and normally what happens after about
the third or fourth time
[sighs]
>> because you're on the for network here.
should be.
>> All right. And we are
not behind a proxy in a firewall, right?
This is just
>> tell you, but I assume not.
>> Yeah.
>> Do you want to do the direct line and
see?
>> Sure.
Okay, this guy.
Okay.
[clears throat]
>> So, in other words, what we're saying is
we're no longer going to use Wi-Fi.
We are Okay. All right. So, that's
Turn the Wi-Fi off.
Uh, turn the Wi-Fi off.
My apologies. We shouldn't be running
into this trouble.
Should
you try to get a new token or something
just in case?
>> I'm sorry.
>> Should you try to get a new token or
>> uh sure we can
uh cancel
uh
let's go ahead and try this from the
beginning.
Dark mode.
Call it account with a subscription.
Um, completely new tab.
>> Try the Wi-Fi again.
>> I'm sorry. Do you want to try the Wi-Fi
again?
>> I don't think. So local host is trying
to connect locally. So that should work,
right? Without any Wi-Fi
>> because the internet is connecting. You
get a reply back on the local host.
>> Yeah.
>> So then it it doesn't seem to be able to
open your port locally.
>> Okay.
>> Are you running it in a dev container?
No, this is
>> No, I'm running it in the browser.
>> Okay.
Oh, but your local host is uh you should
is that port forward in your dev
container?
>> No, it
>> Okay. Sorry.
>> I have I have seen that error before and
what I've done is
is I've been able to do that. Um
So if you take that port 37335
and you in your code spaces you add this
as a port forwarding
to think where that is again
>> but the thing is at that point it's not
it's not in the code spaces
>> but your code spaces need to for your
local host port which is the port
mapping
and then your local host URL will direct
it to the code space.
So usually on
this thing here or something it says
like unit
see for the ports right? Okay. So you
see three tree three that's the same
port.
>> It is the same port.
>> Okay. So it is forwarding.
>> Okay. It says your Okay. So it isn't
that. So your port is forward.
>> Yeah.
>> It's just uh if you resolve in your your
Windows machine, right? If you resolve
local host port, does it land?
>> Uh should be local, but you're using an
external DNS. So I'm just Not sure what
we're
>> Well, I'm using whatever DNS comes along
with.
>> Sure. Could you open up a let's say a
CLI, a command prompt or something?
>> What local host is like being local host
and say what?
>> Okay.
saying they were having
>> a lot.
>> Yeah. But
that's something
local host. Okay.
All right.
>> Okay. We've
>> Okay. So, we've we've we've got a couple
of options. All right. Um, this isn't
working for me today, which I apologize
for that. Um, I have done it. What I can
do is walk you through the commands that
I issued, the um, specifications I gave
my team, and the results that we got
back.
if that would be helpful.
So basically
what what would happen is after we
after we um
after we got cloud flow properly
installed and configured or cloud code
properly installed and configured, we
would execute cloud flow. Um, basically
that probably won't work
because [snorts]
essentially
um
there's no um
MPX is not found.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, I got through like we both through
like the blood flow stuff.
>> Got it.
>> So just doing that before we started. So
>> okay.
All right. Um but after that what we
would have done
is let me explode this a little bit.
Basically we would give it um the
following instructions. All right. Um,
and basically
this bullet list I've formatted as a a
big long command string because Claude
flow is um a command um line tool kind
of like claude code is. Um there is a
primitive guey associated with it but
anyway all I'm doing is I'm asking it to
perform a 12 factor analysis on this
application and I'm telling it where the
application source code is. It's in the
code space
and I told it to put the results in
folder 12 factor. I told it to uh I told
it where the 12 factor principles are
documented in case it didn't know. All
right, no magic there. I didn't assume
that it would know. Um I told it that I
want to know where this application
falls short of 12 factor principles so
that I can assess its capability
um for public cloud dynamic scaling and
availability features should it be
deployed there. All right. So I'm being
honest about what I want and why I want
it. I told it not to change the
application yet. I told it that I'm only
interested in the 12 factor analysis.
Don't do anything more and please let me
know if um you needed additional
information. So I give it an option to
come back to me and say hey um Derek if
you gave me this information my analysis
would be better.
And what it came up with,
it did exactly
um what I wanted. And I'm going to pull
up and it's a very detailed analysis. Um
and I'm going to pull up um what the
summary is. Um you can um I will make
sure that this link um is posted after
the uh after the talk. So you can see um
everything, but it it basically gave me
a 12 factor compliance grade for the
application and it went through each of
the 12
factors and told me which factor um the
application was compliant in and which
factor it wasn't. And this is the
summary section, right? So, if we went
down down down below, um, it'll tell me
exactly what the details are for why
it's non-compliant and what was
non-compliant about it and what it
thinks it'd have to change uh to make it
compliant. And about this point, I
usually get a um
get a question about well great this
this report that comes out is very
verbose and it's very detailed but can
you trust it? All right. Um, and the way
I would cast that conversation is what
we're what we're choosing is I can give
this work for a 12 thou 12 factor
analysis
um an audit of an existing source code
base. I can give that to an automated
team like my cloud code team or I can
give that to a human team. In either
case, with what I get back, I trust but
verify.
All right. So I don't take anything um
verbatim. And so what I would do is go
through in detail um what um what it
considers blockers, what it considers
ready. And I would basically go um
validate that as an architect.
Now, we can see that one of the um one
of the reasons that um it it failed is
because some of the um security
requirements for some of these security
standards aren't met. And it very well
might be that
in my particular installation,
I might be in an enterprise that doesn't
have to be concerned about these
particular security standards. And I
didn't, as you recall the instructions
that I gave it, I didn't tell it what
security standards we had to apply and
what, you know, we could, you know, not
have to deal with. All right? And so
it's basically making an assumption. All
right. Yes, sir.
>> I appreciate what you're doing here. I
really like you have specifying exactly
what
team is expecting, right? Like why
why are you putting this in the space of
using clog flow over using any other
coding system? Like why do you think CL
is good at this versus using?
Okay, that's a very good question. The
question is why Claude flow versus some
other tooling.
>> All right. Um, what happens under the
covers with claude flow is there's a
coordinator that looks at the request
that I give it and it decides
um what kind of team it needs underneath
with what kind of stills, right? whether
it needs more researchers or whether it
needs more analysts or whether it needs
more coders or whether it needs testers,
that kind of thing. And in this case,
for this kind of analysis, it probably
wouldn't allocate a tester at all,
right? You probably
>> And those roles are drawn from a roster
that exists within the flow.
>> Correct.
>> You're not you're not modifying
specifications the schema for those
roles.
>> That's correct.
>> Create your own custom Yeah, you you you
you are talking to somebody that doesn't
go for complexity unless I have a
business need to do it.
>> All right. Um, Claude Flow out of the
box has 16 different agent rules that it
can
apply to a specific problem. It has
right around at last count 60 or 70
different 70 different uh MCP toolings
that come preconfigured right out of the
box that I don't have to configure. I
can configure additional ones if I want
to. Right? But unless I have a business
need to do that, I don't. All right. One
of the reasons I love about this uh one
of the things I love about this tech
stack is and we didn't see it today, but
usually it just works.
All right. And I don't have to
preconfigure it. Um if I you can create
teams of agents
with other tech stacks, but what you get
stuck with is micromanaging that team.
All right, Cursor just uh basically
released an ability where you could run
multiple agents to do multiple things
within the IDE. But it's still incumbent
upon me as a user to figure out, okay,
this agent is going to do that task,
this agent is going to do that task. And
I by nature I'm not a micromanager,
right? If I don't have to micromanage, I
would rather not. I would rather deal
with what outcomes I want and what the
specifics are for those outcomes and
validating that I got what I ask for.
That's what I want to concentrate on
and that's why I use this tech stock.
All right. Did that answer your
question?
>> No. I start.
So, so yeah, that's that's that's
basically what I did. Um, and
I basically offline went through um each
of these uh failures. It apparently
requires sticky sessions, which means
you can scale up, but you can't scale
down. things along those lines get um um
get uh make it make it hard to like
dynamically scale and it also makes it
hard to automatically fail over. There
are a variety of ways to solve that
problem, right? You can put the state in
the client. You can adopt some sort of
um memory cache like Reddus or something
along those lines to to um manage the
state. Um but essentially
essentially um you know there are ways
to solve that problem but they're not
currently solved.
So we would have touh do that if we
wanted to dynamically scale. And I I
basically went through
um each and every one of these things
um items. Um
and basically for the large for the
large part of it um I kind of agreed
with what it came up with. There were
some items that I might have graded as
not critical but
[sighs and gasps]
high or something along those lines, but
to me that's a nit.
Okay. Now,
after after doing that and
having it um if I needed to re uh plan
it, I could. The the next thing I did is
I basically said, "Okay,
use the 12 factor analysis you
documented
um in this folder. Um I told it again
where the principles are just so that it
didn't forget. Um, I wanted it to
document an implementation plan to
upgrade this application so that it
meets all the 12 factor um principles
and place that implementation uh plan
and folder 12 factor plans. Assume the
implementation will be performed by
Agentic engineers using cloud flow and
cloud code. Um, claude code is very
quaint. If you don't tell it that, what
it'll do is assume that you're giving it
to a human team.
And the reality is I'm not.
All right. So, basically, I told it not
to um not to change the application yet,
but let me know if it needed needed
anything.
Um and
and basically
um I got I got a plan and then I
enhanced it.
All right. And I will show you what I
did.
>> I'm sorry.
The thing is flow is really variable
though like I've noticed that like I've
used it for a number of projects like
you ask it to do the same thing twice
like 20 minutes versus 10 it does the
same thing like that that's why I'm kind
of asking a question about flow because
like
>> it's I know you can dig in and say hey
these are the types of agents it's going
to be employing
>> but like you start to compound variance
like when you're enlisting a team of
like six different roles the variability
in which those roles conducted and then
how those roles then collaborate you're
compounding like
>> so spread is huge in terms of like how
you execute task like that's I I
appreciate the power of all the agencies
>> but like how to operationalize them and
say hey I want it to 10 minutes instead
of 20 is tough like that's kind of
>> you don't get to pick that
>> you don't get
>> but I kind of need it because my project
has to be done by Friday
>> do it you'll be fine
like to kind of see what people's
experiences.
>> No,
>> no, you you you are absolutely right.
>> Between the agents, between
>> No, you don't bunch of things into into
flow. You don't know where the like
there's a bottleneck somewhere.
>> No, I think from like even just from the
other sessions that we had today, right,
like which is like how can you have more
controllability? How can you be a bit
more you want to get to a place where
you have like the minimum viable prompt
in order to task, right?
as possible. I think when you have like
frameworks like this, you marry those
two things together, you get to a place
where you can lower that variability.
>> I think you need visibility before that
like like I feel like I feel like we're
flying blind a little bit with this.
>> Okay,
>> we're letting it go. I'm not it's not
not you. It's we let it go and we just
like it's keeps going. Like I like
Claude started adding stuff like the
usage command, things like that. It'd be
really good and it's it's the future in
the environment
>> to have the sub aents you know, kind of
know where you are. If you if you launch
10 sub agents,
>> you don't just want to come back in like
three hours. You want to know like,
>> yeah,
>> how far are each of them done? Like what
are they doing?
>> Well, I mean, hang
hang on for a second. Part of this is
what you what you apply clogged flow
for.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Right. And basically,
um, it's uses LLM at the, uh, at at the
back end, right? which means it's
non-deterministic.
Had this workshop worked as planned and
we were all running um 12 factor
analysis, I can guarantee you that the
reports for each one of us would have
been slightly different.
>> It may have caught some of the same
things, but the format would have been
different or whatnot. And that's that's
a in my mind that's okay. That's a nit
because at this level um we're not
putting that analysis into production.
>> I think it's fine that it's not
deterministic but not knowing
where you are whether you're 5% done or
>> you
>> like you don't know where how far down
you are that's not your problem.
So if you build a role which is actually
a report out agent get that actually
similar to a backlog ID that I completed
I think
>> and kind of marry the two a little bit
so you have like intermediate visibility
and some like tools allow you to and
it's actually one of the challenges
while agents are running a long time you
want to sometimes nudge them in the
middle and say no no
>> stop
Correct.
>> But you also just can't really one shot
long for tasks, right? Like Adobe's uh
what's it no benchmark basically showed
that performance over long form tasks
basically like eventually degrade. And
it inherently makes sense, right? You
have an LLM, it's probabilistic. Let's
say 5% of the time it's going to
hallucinate something. to compound a
bunch of tasks all uh over there.
Anything that you do for a longer period
of time in that probabilistic scenario
magnifies the error rate, right? So if
you don't steer like in certain phases
that you end up basically completely
derailing and then you just end up
having a total garbage or like even
worse super subtle bugs that in logic
that you don't notice until you ship the
product which we like see
usage,
>> right? I mean your your your points are
well taken. Um a couple of work habits
that I've adopted in this world that may
be of use is I don't send cla my claim
cla flow team off to do something that I
know is going to take 5 minutes, 10
minutes, 15 minutes, whatever that time
frame is. I'll start it and then I'll go
do something else. I'll come back to it
in a half hour or whatnot. and I've just
gotten used to working that way. The
other thing that's critical in this
world, whether you're using Claude Flow
or whether you're using Cursor or
Windsurf or whatever um AI coding agent
that that you're using, um [snorts]
basically source control discipline is
critical. You've always got to get be
able to get back to a a known good. So,
I feature branch everything, right? and
I I limit what you know is what work is
in that feature branch and after I've
validated it it it goes into the trunk
right um basically before this world I
used to like a year year and a half ago
I used to rarely throw away feature
branches right now I throw away a good
30% of them it's just part of the
process right I don't look at that is a
bad thing. That's something that Derek
has to do differently and that's okay.
This old dog does occasionally learn new
tricks. So,
anybody heard of JJ as an alternative to
get which is very lightweight
branches of local
commits and then you can define what is
the actual commit. So it's like a pre
like local
>> pre for like instead of not squashing it
take.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It's like you can pick or
whatever but it's a very light way. So I
see some people using this as the local
snapshot like feature pro.
>> Yeah. So I use JJ for this system
pushing it up.
>> Yeah.
So, so there there are some habits that
in my mind you need to uh are are best
kind of learned. So,
>> um but you're right.
>> Is there any uh additional tooling that
you actually build on top of Cloudflow
because Cloudflow just from a cursory
like scan of the codebase has a ton of
stuff, right? So that basically
>> Oh, it is
>> you. If a lot of these things are
basically being automatically activated,
how do you tune it?
>> You know what I'm saying? Like if you
>> time time out. I'll I'll I'll segue back
to a statement I made earlier. You're
talking to somebody that doesn't accept
additional complexity unless I actually
have a business need to do it. So if I I
I have in my back pocket there are
backdoor tunables to claude flow should
the need arise right but to date I've
been using this scene for about six
months which is an eternity in this
business right that's about
>> 10 years
>> yeah about
>> 10 years these days um I have not had a
need to have to do that um at one point
in time I was if If you look at the
Cloudflow documentation, they want you
to use the uh alpha alpha label um by
default. For a while, I was using native
because I'm using it to actually do
work, right? For a while there, um
upfront and early alpha was just too
alpha for me. I ran into too many
runtime problems, but other than that, I
haven't had to tune anything.
Um, and like I said, it's not
that the world's been perfect, but more
often than not, the errors I run into
are my errors.
It went off into never neverland because
I gave it a vague instruction.
And so when I realized that, I basically
go back to the known good. I fix my
instruction and I redo it.
Right. I I don't try to fix something
that got polluted down the road because
that's that's hard. Um and somebody
mentioned um introducing uh bugs that
you don't notice.
I religiously pay attention to my code
coverage stats, right? Um because you're
right. Um, if you tell it that you want
all tests passing, there's a temptation
for it to jimmy the test so that it's
passing even though it's not really
testing anything. So I I pretty much
insist on looking at code coverage, you
know, has has is it in the preferably 75
to 85 percentile range somewhere around
in there is what I've arbitrarily
settled on. Some people will go higher,
some people will go lower. That's a
subjective call on my part. What ends up
happening is you can decree that, okay,
I want you to do 100% coverage, but then
what happens is your test code balloons
because now it's got to mock everything
over God's green earth.
So, you know, you get additional
complexity that you don't necessarily
want.
So, um,
I would look at cases where something
shipped
and I didn't notice. I would basically
go beef up my test cases so that, you
know, whatever
whatever ended up shipping um doesn't
happen again.
So, and I've seen some material, some
people get um um gonzo about protecting
their tests. I've seen some people will
physically separate their test code from
their implementation code and they'll
make their test codes more acceptance
test level rather than unit test level.
Um, and they'll remove it for a separate
repo so that whatever agents are
manipulating your code can't [snorts]
make it easier on themselves by omitting
the tests.
>> Yeah, I
I don't think that like it's necessarily
to do with them not generating a test. A
lot of times they'll generate the tests
that are either totally or will
generate very subtle changes to the
tests that might be hard to catch in
like features.
>> Yeah.
>> So you'll end up it'll be in that like
rough 80% range.
>> Uh but you'll just not have uh the tests
actually won't be be there. And you like
you could argue that
>> yeah just code review better. Uh, but a
lot of times when you have a like pretty
big PRs and you're constantly reviewing
PRs, both yours and others, uh,
eventually you'll have like regressions,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> So, I mean, manual manual um, CRS, what
ends up happening there, like you said,
the volume of them gets to you after a
while, so people rubber stamp them. What
I've seen some people do is have one
agentic AI grade do the pull request for
the output of another. Right? So for
instance uh the um GitHub copilot agent,
right? If you subscribe to that um that
service, it can like do PRs for every
poll request that you do. And in my
case, if I've got Claude code and Claude
flow
generating and changing my code, right,
co-pilot basically doing a PR request on
it. you've got one agent grading
another, but you still run into the the
um issue you talk about where it's um it
looks like spam at some point because
there are just too much too many things
happening at this point. I guess what I
come back to is I care more about what
I try to test at an acceptance test
level. in other words, closer to what
the user
actually uh actually does. And I want to
make sure that those that those work. Um
unit tests are a little bit too closely
bound to the code itself
for my tastes. Um so I I I more
concentrate on that. Um but like there's
no perfect answer to that question. No
matter what,
no matter what puts the code there or
the code changes there, sooner or later
defects will get out the door. But I
look at that at a higher level. Um I I I
measure Doro stats and that kind of
stuff pretty pretty closely. If my
defect rate goes up, then it's a pretty
much uh a indicator that there's
something wrong systemically. I need to
uh I I need to deal with if my defect
rates and my throughput rates and my
velocity are my Dora stats, all four of
them or five of them, whatever they are
now, um are are in aggregate looking
good, then yes, I'm still going to get
the occasional defect that goes out the
door, but it's a question of odds,
right? Nothing's ever going to be
perfect. Yeah.
>> All right. So, I'll get off my soap box.
[clears throat]
>> Yes, sir.
>> Question. Um, so this is a pretty
passive process here and low risk,
right? We're just generating reports.
>> Yes.
>> Um, do you have use cases in which you
use this to actually change code at new
features? like how tell me about maybe a
couple use cases that
>> I personally do not use it to actively
change
commit and deploy code to environments.
I insist on a human in the loop. All
right. I'm completely comfortable with
an agent going through and saying,
"Okay, you're getting this error. I'm
going to propose this fix. Here is a PR
>> [panting]
>> I'm completely cool with that, right?
But I want a human in the loop there
somewhere. I've just seen too many
horror stories. Now, maybe we might get
there someday and I would feel more
comfortable with that. But right now, I
don't.
>> You've had flow agents like agents that
write code, but in the rules, you're
essentially saying you, you know, you
can create all these new features, but I
want a human motor loop. I want you to
create a PR, whatever. Something like
that.
>> Right. Right. And in fact, git I pretty
much declare as that's human oversight.
All right. So I basically say, okay,
cloud flow and cloud code. Here's your
feature branch. I want this behavior
coming out of it. Make these changes,
but I don't trust it with the power to
go ahead and and and merge that feature
branch to main.
Right. I I I I want to I want to see the
uh code coverage at the end of it. I
want to I um if there's any part of it
that looks fishy or whatnot, you know,
occasionally uh not that I like manual
testing at all, but something some
people need that or some things need
that. And somebody's calling me
and
they can go away.
So you had a question
>> just an observation throughout the whole
talk you've been talking about your dev
team as if the agenic
um agents
>> were your team to me that's a huge mind
shift um that's only happened in the
last year so previously I ran a dev team
with 20 folks
>> six months happened within the last six
months
>> uh and having used these same same tools
I also referred to Tom as my dev team,
but I thought I was a weirdo.
>> Welcome to the club.
>> We all like you guys. Um, that's just
speaking for myself, but um,
>> meet a f fellow weirdo.
>> And um, as someone who was responsible
for hiring, recruiting, training, you
know, I looked at my dev team, a typical
team of six, front end, backend, devops,
that was a million dollars a year
domestically, right? each of those
wonderful people getting, you know, good
salary, overhead benefits, blah, blah,
blah. I complain now when I spend $100 a
day on that same group of people, quote
unquote, agents doing this code, right?
So that that economic shift, even if
it's got bugs, you know what my people
did and they called in sick. I'll pick a
few relative rate of bugs in the door
metrics for someone who never falls in
polite.
>> Yeah.
>> And cost me fractions, you know, pennies
on the dollar what I would pay out the
door for these for these again talented,
[snorts] lovely folk that I enjoy
working with every day.
>> Yeah. Well,
I don't believe that um Derek's going
anywhere anytime soon because of uh
Claude Flow and Claude Code or I don't
believe Frank's going anywhere.
>> I don't know about Frank Jr.
>> the next folks come out of school,
>> you know, how are they going to get the
experience? I know what Ron looks like.
I don't I don't think it's about about
the
age or experience. It's the relative
ability because I think you can find
people that are juniors and or seniors.
I don't want to be agist or reverse ages
where I've seen people that are juniors
>> that are that pick this stuff up really
quick.
>> Sure.
>> I've also seen people that are seniors
that kind of clock in and get attendance
to be here. Yeah,
>> it's not I don't think it's about junior
versus more about
>> engineering. A higher order of
engineering capability is required for
this.
>> The the the phrase I use for that is
there's a difference between 20 years of
experience and one year experience 20
times
what good looks like. So I I I get this
argument quite often like okay the
younger generation how you going to
learn but when you talk to the younger
generation they say we can learn so much
faster because it's kind of constantly
helping us to level up. Of course you
need to have that skill and so on but
they can they have like this continuous
finger required as like years of know
tissue.
>> Yeah. So there's a balance, you know, in
both, but the ability to adapt and to
learn to suck it out. Yeah,
>> I do I like what you're saying, but I
don't know that it's
>> fair.
I had just my team
is I had, you know, five decades. that
somebody in their 20s and somebody in
their 70s all contributed uh and I
always worried about how do I continue
to advance my new buyers
um in their career
um for the next decade
>> and this whole world is so new we don't
have a definitive playbook for how we
grow um seniors um when that question
comes up things that I try is kind of
what um I do with juniors a day. I visit
them twice a day. I I I I I look in on
how they're doing and the questions are
different. It's like don't don't don't
show me what what code you've done. You
know, what what have you instructed your
Claude flow team to do and how's it
working? you know, are they spinning or
you know, what what what what's um
what's constructively
um been improved on and what are you
having trouble with? And if they're
having trouble with something, I may
pair with them and have them show me
their instructions,
right? And then more often than not, I
can help coach them about how to make
those instructions
um better. Cuz to to my my way of
thinking, it's not that the work's going
away. It's that the skill set and the
the the talents that are needed are
different and they're changing. And
basically what I tell people is that uh
you know this world is coming. You may
not agree with it. You may not like it
but denial is not a great strategy.
Don't do it.
>> Yes. Just to comment on that,
um I think for younger engineers, the
desired skill set is just different and
the best young engineers are going to be
uh those who understand how to use tool
like this tools like this and have good
ideas because like you said like your
scenario where you get rid of six people
and you can get the same work done.
Yeah.
you're saving a million dollars a year
to do the same amount of work. I think
on the other end, there are going to be
companies that say, "Let's hire four
guys that can each do what you're doing
with those agents and invest a million
dollars to for revenue."
>> You know what I mean?
>> Yeah, absolutely. And if you can have
that more revenue, that's a great
strategy.
>> Yeah. But it's
>> some of our stuff boundary condition
just
>> in DevOps we automated a lot of stuff
and a lot of people said oh
I don't need to understand all the stuff
if you look at the whole progression we
had tests first we had like automation
then we had test okay we were talking
about testing being able to do that well
you got like observability came up like
I want to see what's happening I want to
understand I want to dig in okay similar
And then in the end we had like chaos
engineering and chaos engineering was
actually to be prepared when things
fail. So as the tools are progressing
and getting better somebody stepping in
at the moment of need a kind of
situational awareness saying yes no to
even the agent
>> that is like a fireman preparing for
that. And you know you can prepare and
learn but a lot of companies might not
say we're going to keep teaching you
just in case. they might skip that like
investment but when you're going to need
it you got to call the notes
>> I think you got to keep teaching
yourself as an individual
>> but one thing to point about your your
de the devops resolution is I feel that
in most cases made us go faster not have
less cost
>> we just everything just started going
faster
>> this will probably be the same most
people won't use this or won't be able
to reduce cost with
Most people, you know, they'll be able
to go faster if they're good,
>> but I don't think many people are able
to reduce cost.
>> Although the craft when they become
craft, oh, it's going to be automated,
they say, well, not everybody can do
this, right? In essence, what happens?
The craft becomes for a while kind of
commodity and then the people doing
this, they become specialized, right?
Because they take on bigger chunks, more
complex stuff like you know, one person
dealing with 10 AI agents and that's
>> [clears throat]
>> that common pattern of some something
that gets more common but then
eventually it becomes like a higher
level of education.
>> That's right. I mean I I I don't think
uh coding is actually going away but
what I think is the what um a colleague
termed as commodity coders.
coders where you say, "All right, I need
a class that does this, that, and the
other thing." And you go code it and
return it and you're done. And and you
don't care about where that class is
used and and and and what function it it
it actually serves and what you're
building. Those commodity coders
basically are are are likely to go away.
But that doesn't mean the work goes
away. That means it shifts.
I think that's coding versus
engineering.
>> Yes.
>> Like the code typing the code in will go
away. You don't have [laughter]
to type it. Good.
>> We keep saying
>> understanding it is different.
>> You need professional critical thinkers.
>> Yes.
>> Well, my wife, she's a photographer and
I can take pretty pictures with my
iPhone, but I can't like whatever.
[laughter] She'll take a better picture
even without any of my fun stuff. And
it's the same thing. You have people who
come.
>> Yeah. And in fact, I I see similar
rookie mistakes. The first thing that um
coders who try to get into this world
try to do is they try to micromanage it.
I want it to produce code exactly like I
would have produced it. All right? And
that's the wrong way to think about it.
they need to evolve to think about okay
these are the outcomes I want
I mean I could take the same um
development task and give it to person A
or person B or person C and I'm not
going to get exactly what it would have
been if I had coded it right that's just
not a realistic thing what's realistic
is to expect that it it does what it's
supposed to do and you're concentrating
on the outcomes
And that's the biggest mistake that I
that I see. The other confusion I see is
there's a wide variance depending upon
what tooling you're using. All right.
Um, one of my clients took about 18
months just over to clear um, GitHub uh,
co-pilot within Visual Studio Code with
the legacy chat GPT uh, 4 models, right?
Um, and at one point in time that was
state-of-the-art 18 months ago. I get
that. But now it's in the rearview
mirror and it's getting smaller every
day, right? And
I talked to somebody who is is is
compelled to use that because of where
they work and they don't have the same
kind of good experience that I have with
Cloud Code and Cloudflow.
>> And that's just going to be part of our
world. Um I used to pride myself on
being at the forefront and being able to
stay at the forefront of everything. And
I've gotten used to the fact that I am
just barely keeping up.
>> Been talking for two hours. I'm sure
things came out today.
>> We missed something.
>> Yeah. Gemini 3 anti-gravity.
[laughter]
>> I wonder when you say well don't look at
the code and kind of work on the
outcomes. Uh the flip side that I have
in my head is when it fails, you need to
kind of somehow dig in and kind of help
it, right? So it's a little bit of like
>> that's that that that's a very good
point. I see another rookie what I
consider a rookie mistake and maybe
that's a harsh assessment is somebody
concentrating on outcomes, getting an
error, and then immediately getting out
their debugger and looking at a code
level. All right. And there's a step or
two in between there. All right. So, one
of the things that I do is basically
when it's obvious that I've given the
same type of error back to my team and
it's not getting fixed, I'll start
asking my tween detailed questions. All
right. And often times in that
conversation, I'll figure we'll between
the team and I will figure out what the
issue is. and I never got to the code
level to begin with. And I'll give you a
concrete example. Um, one of my uh
Golang projects um was bombing in its
build step. The the llinter uh that goes
through and make sure that uh Golang is
uh structured correctly or whatnot that
Golang has a has a llinter for that
purpose. and it just wasn't it wasn't
passing after two or three times giving
it to my cloud flow team basically they
weren't uh they weren't getting any
closer and then in that conversation
with my team basically we figured out
that in the build workflow I had a
llinter that was about six or seven
months old
and my cloud flow team was doing back
flips because what it had you access to
was a lot more current than that. And so
I basically instructed my team that no,
go upgrade the workflow, the build
workflow so that it uses a more current
uh version of the llinter and we were
fine. We stopped spinning, right? But in
that case, I didn't get down to code
level, right? I mean, I got stack trace
errors, and anybody who prides
themselves on being able to get to a
code level error and debug a a stack
trace or whatnot, um, hops at it
because, uh, it's it's a world that
they're comfortable with. What I'm
trying to impress upon you is that
there's a there are a couple steps you
go through before you get to that step.
Did that make any sense?
It's all um very resonant with a bunch
of experiences.
>> So
>> yeah, and and often times that is kind
of congruent with comparing it to like a
a junior uh or a human team.
You wouldn't necessarily as a good
manager go micromanage
somebody
um under you being a human. I wouldn't
want to jump to that as the first level
in this world either.
Now,
maybe uh
maybe I'll get riots in the streets over
that statement, but
>> sometimes my will vary.
[gasps]
>> [panting and sighs]
>> But, uh, no, I mean, I I I use this
stack day in day out. And
somebody could come out with something
better next week.
And the truth is, I have no allegiance
to this. If somebody shows me something
better and I play around with it and I
agree that it is better.
I'm sorry Ruben who creates Cloudflow
but no I'm I'm moving on.
>> I don't know if this has been addressed
but uh have you seen like huge token
usage from Flow? Like how bad am I going
to spend my company's API?
>> That that that is a very good uh
question. I had to bump my subscription
to the uh to the max subscription for um
hundred bucks a month.
>> Yeah, luckily that's not too bad,
>> right? Well, no. I mean, it's it's not
cheap. I hesitated doing it, but I
pretty much figured out that all right,
another uh Derek philosophy is we're all
responsible for our own skill sets,
right? And if I don't have an employer
that's going to fund that hundred bucks
a month and I perceive that I really
need to learn how to get into this
business, I'm going to do it at least
for a while.
>> I have one more followup question for
you. Uh have you gone into depth in
terms of customizing cloud flow for
specific development areas? I'm a
Salesforce architect so my focus is in
Salesforce stuff but I'm wondering if
there's been a lot of
>> I have not had a need to I have seen the
material about how I could go do that
and micromanage what types of agents it
spins up in the team that it um it uses
how I could configure my own agents with
their own roles if you know I had a
specific need and none of the 16 that
comes with Claude flow
really matches what um I want to do. I I
realize that I can go do that. But
you're talking to somebody that doesn't
do the complexity just because it's the
shiny object in the corner, right?
That's that's that's not me. If I have a
specific need, I need to go do that. I
know I can and I'll go figure it out.
But I haven't had the need to do that.
>> I wonder what you think about. So I I've
been building my own like sub agent
swarms myself just with specific
Salesforce MCPs and uh stuff that I
think would be helpful for Salesforce
projects. Um but it feels like Cloudflow
is just like a super polished version of
that with more tooling that's available
for kind of any any size fits all
projects. Yeah, I have no doubt that um
when you put your own custom team
together,
>> you are probably
you are probably getting less token
usage. You are probably you are probably
having an incremental um improvement
over what the generic cloud flow would
do. Then it's a costbenefit thing,
right? Is the additional work worth 10
or 20% better? In some cases, it might.
In some cases,
no. You go with a general and you do
your specific tuning on the cases where
you need to.
>> There's also the benefit of learning how
to work as an agent, which is
>> Yeah. fun.
>> Well, no. And I I understand that, too.
>> Sometimes you do things for fun. I get
that. It looks like it's mostly one guy.
2900 commits.
>> Yeah,
>> just one guy. No,
>> the next is Claude. Claude is the next
with 180. The third highest committer in
CL in club. Seven commits.
>> Wow.
>> It is.
>> I'm not saying he's not good, but it's
one guy.
>> Well, not not only that, but he eats his
own dog food.
>> Oh, no. I'm just rough. Ruff kind of the
other, you know, it's been going on for
a long time and really is leading the
space. So of course he's like one of the
core committers because he's leading a
lot of people. There's a whole community
around that which is the engineer a
genetic engineering group and they're
helping him but obviously he's like
pushing.
>> He's a little bit ahead of him
>> but he's not alone in that perspective.
He has like a community around that that
is helping him but he's always pushing.
So that's why why he's like
he is working a lot on the token usage.
uh like recently also with new MCP
features he was able to drop like the
whole token so he's aware he's also has
to pay his bills
there I have one question one for sure
>> in a way like it was briefly mentioned
but let's say I have specific knowledge
sales force knowledge something I've got
over the years how do you provide that
to flow right because the 12 factor is
is wildly known but like you specifics.
>> Well, I mean, in in in terms of
specifying what you want Claude Flow to
do, if you can verbalize
what that what that knowledge is and can
tell the Cloudflow team about it, it can
it can work with it.
>> So, you provided like pros and cons with
like your knowledge or specific or
>> Right. Um, for example, um, we did we
planned a rather large, um,
implementation for a large financial
institution. Um, and I can't name the
financial institution because we
technically weren't supposed to do that
planning with Claude Flow outside of
their uh, their environment. Um
>> but uh but basically it came out with a
plan and right away we saw that okay in
this environment these things aren't
actually technical problems. They're
they're requests to be filed with
different teams. All right. um in this
um environment at this stage we have to
go to the governance board for approval
for this that or the other thing. My
team didn't know anything about that.
All right. So with that specialized
knowledge we put we we documented that
in a markdown and told claude flow about
it and told it to reassess its plan and
it it did that. But what it came down to
is me identifying what that knowledge
was and me having the English skills to
be able to
put it and mark down that I could hand
to Claude Flo. Um another actually um
along those lines another technique that
I use sometimes is I ask my team to
explain its thinking step by step.
And the reason I do that is because
often times when it makes assumptions,
if you don't tell it to show its work
step by step, sometimes those
assumptions kind of get buried. Whereas
if you um tell it to show its thinking
step by step, you can see those
assumptions often times being made and I
can say, "Oh, I see why it made those
assumptions. I didn't tell it anything
differently. That's not their fault.
That's my fault.
And I will go clarify those instructions
so that they don't have to make those
assumptions." and
go redo whatever it was.
Yes, ma'am.
>> Explain these step-by-step instructions.
Is it consistently giving you the same
assumptions or do the assumptions change
over time?
Um I gen Okay the question as I
understand it and I'm repeating it so
people in the front of the room can hear
it is that um do you let the team make
assumptions or
>> when you ask it to explain it step by
step
>> yes
>> do you find that it gives you consistent
answers for the assumptions that it's
making or do you find that it changes
over time?
>> Um I
That's a good question. Um, I believe
that if I gave it the same thing and
told it to reflect its thinking step by
step, since LLMs aren't um,
deterministic, they would be subtle
differences between those executions.
But more likely than not, it will tell
me explicitly what it's assuming
and why it's thinking what it's
thinking. And that's the information
that I want. All right. Um, and I'm not
trying to get you to get people to say
that we never let the team make
assumptions because it's it's they may
make a hundred assumptions and 80 80% of
them might be fine, right? You might
only have
issues with 20% of them or 10% of them
or something along those lines. Um, but
you
and it takes I I I guess I wouldn't make
the um make the mistake of being
unnecessarily specific until I had a
need. And when I ask for step-by-step uh
documentation and I'm reading through
what it thought and how it went through
this,
I might see a need to say, "Okay, I
don't want it making an assumption about
this." And so out of those that long
list litany of assumptions it made, I
might take the effort to say, "Okay, I'm
going to give you decisions on two of
them." And sometimes, you know, that uh
statement at the end of those
instructions, I usually put um where um
I ask it to uh let me know if it needs
anything.
Sometimes I'll get in the markdown,
usually buried at the bottom. It'll have
a series of questions and basically say,
"Okay, you need to make a decision about
these five things."
and I'll usually listen and I'll usually
uh make a decision about those things
and have it replant.
All right. I I generally
um
I've gotten conditioned to look for
those paragraphs,
but that's just me. Did that answer your
question?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> I have a different question
around
you know, automation to testing to obser
like governance play a role in that. Is
it because we don't have government up
front and we're doing all of these
progression that then there's this chaos
engineering. Um the question is where
does governance play a role
um in this
>> or at the end
>> and in in the front or the end? Um for
me personally since I don't let my team
merge
um branches into trunk or whatnot the
the governance is really a human looking
over that poll request.
Um, and what I do personally in addition
to looking over that poll request, I may
not look over the code changes line by
line, but I pay a lot of attention to my
code coverage and what changes you made
to the tests. I want to make sure that
you're not just you neutering the tests
just to get my get get past my 80%
threshold request.
Right? So
that is different than the governance
that you would normally do with a human
team. You look at the changes line by
line. That's pretty common.
I tend not to do that. I look at the
outcomes and I look at the test for the
outcomes and I look at the defect rates.
>> I think I see people do it at at
different places. So you know if your
security has some kind of guidance or
DevOps team has some kind of standards
or architecture people put that into
their kind of prompts because it's it
kind of yields already things in the
right direction but the actual kind of
garments it is probably should be more
nondeterministic. So you put it there
then the reviewing kind of give you
feedback you have to make a decision and
hopefully there's more enforcement point
happening as well. So if you do it here.
You're going to have to like go back
into the room. But it's a like Derek
says, it's a balance. If you do it too
straight, nothing will it will grant
here. But having some notions, the broad
strokes already puts it in the right
direction.
>> That's that's true. So I guess I would
paraphrase it and say that that
governance changes in this world, but
it's still there.
That's how I would phrase it.
>> That makes sense. I guess I'm curious.
You mentioned that if it was a human,
you would review every line, but if it's
an agent, you wouldn't. So, I'm just
that kind of philosophical shift to
>> Well, you the the the reason I'm
shifting my focus as and no longer
looking at changes line by line is that
there are too many lines changed, right?
Um I look at it as a continuum, right?
uh let's say a completely human
non-aggentic AI kind of team like we
used to have two or four or five years
ago whatnot. All right, you give them a
story to work on. You give them a change
to work on and it's generally framed so
that they could make that change within
a couple days. Right? If it's longer
than that, it's generally too large of a
story. All right? So you take that
definition in today's world
and on the other end of the continuum is
a oneshot deal where you know build me
an application from scratch that does
everything and including you know
buttered my toast and and and and and
[laughter] whatnot. There's a continuum
in between there. And [snorts] what I
would think or what I think is that with
this world
that optimal story size moves a little
bit this direction. It's not at the
other end of the continuum, but it moves
a little bit this direction. And when
that happens, those commits get larger,
right? And if I'm looking at u 40 lines
being changed, that takes me x amount of
time. I'm confronted with the PR from
this world that might have thousands of
lines of change and I'm not going
through that line by line. I just don't
have the time or the bandwidth.
>> Some people have been experimenting with
so you know you can find code in that
right. So that's one way you give it all
the instruction to saw somebody who did
actually what after it was coded he
asked code can you prove it's working?
So it's a different call back of course.
like the reviewer but then what actually
happened was the coding agent started
via coding app that started proving
which basically started implementing the
tests. So it's one way of like helping
us write code but helping us do review
and scale and again there's a talk about
that tomorrow as well but kind of
there's some truth in helping us in that
part as well with coding components or
making it more visual or understandable
like questions you ask about base,
right? So, yeah, definitely makes sense.
>> Yeah. The other side benefit I'm
starting to see is that because I'm
putting behaviors in a specifications
and giving them to my team. In fact, in
other words, I'm writing them down in
enough detail that something can
actually uh um interpret that and try to
implement that. Over time, you have
written documentation as to what the
system does. And occasionally what I'll
do is
basically say, "Okay team,
go look at our team documentation and go
validate that we are actually still
meeting spec and still meeting the
requirements and that we haven't over
time kind of forgotten about uh um this
requirement or that requirement because
um what agents do is they um when they
reach their token limit size, they do
what's called compression, right?
They'll take a look at what they've got
in memory and giving to the LLM and
they'll say, "Okay, I don't need this. I
don't need that. I don't need that." And
what's happening when they do that?
Sometimes they're forgetting about
requirements that were implemented two
months ago,
right? So, um, every every once in a
while I'll I'll do that. But what that
also means is I can have my Cloudflow
team, okay, take our requirements in
this library of markdown files and
produce a uh nice uh a nice document
that I can show to management.
I can do that. And granted, it may not
be exactly what I'll hand to my boss,
but I'll get something a lot closer and
in a lot less time than I would have
otherwise.
And so that that has value, too. I've
seen one team um actually um
basically use MCP tooling to update have
the have their uh claude team update
confluence documentation
based off of based off of changes you're
making or whatnot. And that has uh value
too because not everybody in the
management chain wants to hit a git repo
and look at a markdown file.
>> So you do the same thing with like you
know MCP for jur
>> I'm sorry
>> the same thing you just mentioned with
using MCP to update confluence create
new docs
>> the same thing with with working through
Jira epics and projects.
>> Yeah. Well, I mean to me document
uh and in fact actually that gets me
into another one of my soap boxes. Um
documentation requirements at a code
level are changing now.
>> Right? If I can
po point Claude code or cloud flow or
cursor or one of these tools at a
section of code and tell it hey explain
to me what this thing does. I don't need
that static documentation in the same
way I used to. Yes,
>> that becomes to me that becomes more
like the prompts are important or the
specs are important because you never
should document what code does. You
should document why you did it.
>> That's right.
>> Because if you can't read the code to
tell the code is self-documenting in
some ways and I'm not trying to be
>> yeah,
>> you know, flippant on that, but the code
tells you exactly what it does. You
don't have to say that in English,
>> right? But you should say why you did it
or what it's connected to or what are
some key things. That's important. And I
think now the specs are equally as
important.
>> I think I think you're absolutely right
because that's part that uh cursor or
cloud code can't tell you looking at the
code. They can't tell you why you did X,
Y, or Z,
but your specs probably do.
for your commitment history. [laughter]
[panting]
>> Yeah, but those are large too. So
other
>> sorry, which one of the 12 factors have
you seen the swarm struggle with the
most?
>> Um, which one of the 12 factors have I
seen uh Claude struggle with the most?
The thing that frequently comes up is
sticky sessions in session state because
that kills scale up dynamic scalability
and also kills failover.
All right. Um
it actually if you look at legacy Java
apps
um and I don't want to get into a
religious war. I have a lovehate
relationship, mostly hate with Spring on
the Java side, but it in
but it intensively it incents people to
put default creds in spring property
files
and it insenser
I I'm not Monday morning quarterbacking
the the decision that that that led into
uh that kind of architecture where
that's that that's incented. But the the
truth is Spring apps are very hard to
inject
configuration into
one of the things you want to do. So
when you're talking Java apps,
um configuration is another stumbling
block that I see quite a bit. Um, and
I'm not pick I mean I I I I did Java for
a decade and a half. I wrote a couple
books on it, right? So I I I I [snorts]
come from that world, so I'm not dinging
it. But Java is the new cobalt.
>> What's your What's your preferred
language now?
>> Uh, my preferred language is it it it
actually it it depends. If I'm building
an agent or MCP tooling, it's Python.
And the reason is is that um the tooling
is stronger there as far as third party
tools. Um otherwise it's it's probably
Golang. And since you asked the
question,
often times when I specify a new
application,
I don't micromanage the tooling choice.
I let my team recommend what they want
to do. And if I disagree with it, I look
at it as an architect and I disagree
with it, I may add a constraint
and tell it to re to replan. But what I
find is by micromanaging it up front, I
learn less.
Sometimes they come up with ideas that
are really nice that I didn't think of.
It it seems like uh Python and
TypeScript are the lead for the two
languages that people would likely build
MC.
>> Yes. And and agents for the same reason.
All right. Um
having said that, you know, I know
people doing it in uh Golang. Um,
one of the things I like about Rust or
Golang is the fact that uh it's truly
write once, you know, compile for any
platform and it and it works the same
way pretty much everywhere unless you're
doing device driver level stuff.
>> I think the key word in that sentence
was compile.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. So um and that's one of the
reasons why um Docker uses uh Golang,
Terraform uses Golang, dozens and dozens
if not hundreds of products use Golang
because they don't want to deal with
different executables for
different platforms.
>> It's also beautifully packaged. You
>> get a binary.
>> Yeah, you get a binary. Don't do a fifth
install somewhere and hope that it
works.
>> Yep, that is true. So, did that answer
your question?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay,
>> good conversation.
>> Your wisdom just coming out.
I am I am I I am I am and before uh we
get uh more shrinkage I am really sorry
that the workshop portion of this didn't
work out as well as planned but I
appreciate [snorts]
the fact that people stayed and
conversed about this stuff anyway
>> and I want to thank you like for
recovering and doing this because that's
>> Thank Heat
[music]
up